bs-shipmanagement.com 2018-09-10

# Bernhard Schulte Shipmanagement , Company, Management

This privacy notice is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. [Alternatively, you can download a pdf version of the notice here: [Privacy Policy](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/assets/basicmenu/5/editor/bsm_website_privacy_notice.pdf)]

  **1\. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE**

Bernhard Schulte Shipmanagement (“BSM”) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

**PURPOSE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE**

This privacy notice applies to information obtained through this website and how we use it.

This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements other notices and privacy policies and is not intended to override them. Other specific policies are applied by BSM where your relationship with BSM is that of a representative of a client, a prospective client or other third party professional contact, and that of an employee, contractor or job applicant.

**CONTROLLER**

BSM consists of different legal entities, details of which can be found in <http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/contact>. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of BSM so when we mention” Bernhard Schulte Shipmanagement”, “BSM”, “BSM Group?” “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company in the BSM Group responsible for processing your data.

**CONTACT DETAILS**

If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact our internal GDPR team at privacy@schultegroup.com.

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the concerned supervisory authority for data protection issues. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the supervisory authority so please contact us in the first instance.

**CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES**

We keep our privacy notice under regular review. This version was last updated on 22.06.2018. We will inform you when we update our policy with a link to view historical versions.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

**THIRD-PARTY LINKS**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

2\. **THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

  *   **Identity Data** includes your first name, last name, date of birth, gender, country of citizenship and residence, designation, company name, country
  * **Professional and educational details, username and password** when registering as a job applicant
  * In case of seafarers, we ask for the passport number, seaman book number and closest BSM Center
  * **Contact Data** includes email address, phone number and postal address
  * **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and other technology on the devices you use to access this website
  * **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website and services
  * **Cookies** – We collect information about use of our website through cookies. Please visit our [cookie policy](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/cookie-policy) to learn more
  * **Marketing and Communications Data –** includes your preferences to receive our newsletter “BSM Highlights” and your communication preferences

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data could be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**IF YOU FAIL TO PROVIDE PERSONAL DATA**

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example to provide you our services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

3\. **HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions;** You may give us your Name, Company Name, Designation, Country, email address, phone number, date of birth, Gender, Country of citizenship and residence, professional details by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you apply for our services
  * Request to be considered for employment
  * Create an account on our website
  * Subscribe to our service or publications
  * Request marketing to be sent to you
  * Give us feedback or contact us
  * **Automated technologies or interactions;** As you interact with our website, we will automatically collect technical data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, add-in and other similar technologies. Please see our [cookie policy](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/cookie-policy) for further details
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources;** We will receive Technical Data from analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU

4\. **HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  *  Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data although we will get your consent before sending direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.

**PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data. The legal grounds for processing your data are:

  1. Performance of a contract with you
  2. Necessary for our legitimate interests
  3. Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Type of data  
**

| 

**Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
  
---|---|---  
  
To register you as job applicant (Shore & on board)

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Educational and professional

(d) Username and Password

| 

Performance of a contract with you  
  
To manage our relationship with you which will include:

(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy

(b) to respond to your enquiries

(c) To complete any survey

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our services)  
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

| 

(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To use data analytics to improve our website, services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences

| 

(a) Technical

(b) Usage

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about services that may be of interest to you

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our services and grow our business)  
  
**MARKETING**

We maintain a separate privacy notice about our marketing activities which you can view here <http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/bsm-marketing-privacy-policy>

**PROMOTIONAL OFFERS FROM US**

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, and Usage Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or registered to receive our newsletter “ _BSM Highlights_ ” and to receive information about events and industry news and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

**THIRD-PARTY MARKETING**

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party for marketing purposes.

**OPTING OUT**

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by contacting us at [privacy@schultegroup.com](mailto:privacy@schultegroup.com) at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, product/service experience or other transactions.

**COOKIES**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our [Cookie Policy](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/cookie-policy).

**CHANGE OF PURPOSE**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

**5.** **DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table above.

  *  Internal Third Parties being other companies in the BSM Group which are based in EU as well as in Non-EU countries. For the full list of entities which form part of the BSM Group, with their geographical location, please visit <http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/contact>
  *  We do not share the information we collect about you from the website with any 3rd parties. However, we may share this information with law enforcement agencies, Government and regulatory bodies to meet legal and regulatory obligations

**6\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

We share your personal data within the **BSM Group.** This will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ). Not all countries provide the same level of protection in relation to personal information as within the EEA. Where necessary to make such transfers, we will comply with our legal and regulatory obligations in relation to the personal information. This will include having a lawful basis for transferring personal information and putting appropriate safeguards in place to ensure an adequate level of protection for the personal information.

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

**7\. DATA SECURITY**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

**8\. DATA RETENTION**

**HOW LONG WILL WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR?**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or reporting requirements. We may retain your personal data for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation in respect to our relationship with you.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.

Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available in our Retention Policy which you can request from us by contacting us.

In some circumstances, you can ask us to delete your data: see “Your Legal Rights” below for further information.

In some circumstances, we will anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

**9\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. Please click on the links below to find out more about these rights:

  * _[Request correction of your personal data](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/privacy-policy#correction)_
  * _[Request erasure of your personal data](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/privacy-policy#erasure)_
  * _[Object to processing of your personal data](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/privacy-policy#object_processing)_
  * _[Request restriction of processing your personal data](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/privacy-policy#restriction_processing)_
  * _[Request transfer of your personal data](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/privacy-policy#transfer)_
  * _[Right to withdraw consent](http://www.bs-shipmanagement.com/en/privacy-policy#withdraw_consent)_

You have the right to:

**Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios:

  *  If you want us to establish the data’s accuracy
  * Where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it
  * Where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims
  * You have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it

**Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please Contact us at [privacy@schultegroup.com](mailto:privacy@schultegroup.com)

**NO FEE USUALLY REQUIRED**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we could refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**WHAT WE MAY NEED FROM YOU**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**TIME LIMIT TO RESPOND**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it could take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
